Craig Taylor 80 Edward Tyler Road, London, SE12 9QF (+44)7908 795936

craigtaylor89@yahoo.co.uk
https://www.craig-taylor.co.uk

Profile

Front-End/ Games Developer with experience using C++/C#, Unity3D HTML, CSS, SASS, Javascript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Wordpress, MySQL, PHP and Git.

Passionate and self-driven to develop applications and video games that deliver a lasting impact amongst our target audiences with the means to learn, accept challenges and persevere.

Personal Projects

Udacity Capstone Project | Github Link | Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, Jest, Webpack

 Developed a search engine based on the user's intended travel destination as a keyword, the date of arrival and optionally return before retrieving a picture and the weather forecast of the said destination.

Dungeon Escape | Github Link | Unity3D, C#

- Developed a game called Dungeon Escape is part of a Unity approved course to expand knowledge in C# and utilise the intermediate functionality of the game engine.
- Intentionally will become an ongoing personal project to implement further mechanics and enemy varieties as a resemblance of the Metroidvania genre.

Qualifications

Udacity Front-end Developer Nanodegree – Pass
BA (Hons) Game Design – Tiga Accredited – First Class Honours
BTEC National Diploma for Games Development – DDD (Distinction, Distinction, Distinction)
BTEC First Diploma in IT – Merit
BTEC Introductory Diploma for IT at Work – Distinction

Work Experience

TT Fusion Ltd - QA Tester

July to November 2015

LEGO Marvel's Avengers -PS3/PS4/Xbox 360/Xbox One/Wii U

TT Fusion Ltd. (formerly Embryonic Studios Ltd.) is a British video game developer company and a division of TT Games. Based in Wilmslow, England, United Kingdom

- Conducted Smoke Testing to ensure the player is able to naturally progress from the start of the game without any progression blockers that would ruin the experience.
- Conducted Scripted/Regression/Sweep testing based on Lead QA's instructions and Destructive testing to identify unreported bugs and ensure fixes are in place from Regression testing.
- Observed, analysed and reported evidential bugs using JIRA based on its severity and urgency with Lead QA's approval to ensure upmost quality, challenge and enjoyment upon release.

SEGA Europe Ltd - Functionality Tester

October 2014 to July 2015

SEGA, is a Japanese multinational video game developer and publisher company headquartered in Tokyo, Japan, with multiple offices around the world. Sega developed and manufactured numerous home video game consoles from 1983 to 2001.

Games worked on: Total War: ARENA, Dead Island 2

Other Employment

<u>Homestead LCI - Barista</u>

November 2020 to February 2021

- Listened to customers' orders and delivered coffee/tea drinks at a reasonable timeframe based on urgency and priority.
- Utilised previous experience as a speciality coffee barista to independently open and close the cafe section throughout the day.
- Communicated with customers in a friendly and professional manner while using coffee knowledge to promote retail sales with advice on brewing techniques.
- Trained colleagues on using the espresso machine to improve workflow and knowledge for the foreseeable future.
- Communicated with colleagues based on ongoing orders to create an effective workflow during peak times.